Hanseul Cho (조한슬)

Room 9410, Building No.9., 85 Heogi-ro, Dongdaemun-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea

💌 jhs4015 (at) kaist (dot) ac (dot) kr | 🧥 hanseuljo.github.io | 🖸 github.com/HanseulJo | 🕿 Google Scholar



Personal Profile

I am a Master's student in the Optimization & Machine Learning (OptiML) Laboratory, advised by Prof. Chulhee Yun at Kim Jaechul Graduate School of AI (GSAI) in Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST). Before this, I received my Bachelor's degree in Mathematical Sciences (major) and Computing Sciences (minor) at KAIST in 2022.

My primary research interests lie in optimization, machine learning, and deep learning, mainly focusing on theoretical analysis of them. Recently, I have been looking at bi-level optimization for stochastic/finite-sum settings—including minimax optimization (i.e., saddle point problem), actorcritic algorithms for reinforcement learning, fair machine learning, and more—with particular interest.

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Seoul, Republic of Korea

M.Sc. in Artificial Intelligence

Mar. 2022 - Current

Mar. 2017 - Feb. 2022

· Advisor: Prof. Chulhee Yun (Optimization & Machine Learning (OptiML) Laboratoy, Kim Jaechul Graduate School of AI (GSAI), KAIST)

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

B.Sc. in Mathematical Sciences

• Minor in Computer Sciences

Summa Cum Laude (GPA: 4.05/4.3)

University of Twente Exchange Student Program

• Major in Applied Mathematics

Enschede, Netherlands Feb. 2020 - Jul. 2020

Incheon Science High School

Incheon, Republic of Korea

· Early Graduation

High School

Mar. 2015 - Feb. 2017

Publication

PREPRINTS

• Hanseul Cho and Chulhee Yun. SGDA with shuffling: faster convergence for nonconvex-PŁ minimax optimization. 2022. arXiv:2210.05995. (Preprint Under Review.)

DOMESTIC CONFERENCES/JOURNALS

- Hanseul Cho and Chulhee Yun. SGDA with shuffling: faster convergence for nonconvex-PŁ minimax optimization. Short version in 2022 Korea Al Association + NAVER Autumnal Joint Conference (JKAIA 2022). 2022.
 - NAVER Outstanding Theory Paper Award & Spotlight presentation.

Experiences

Machine/Deep Learning Theory + Physics (MDLTP) Seminar

Seoul, Republic of Korea

Organizer

Jul. 2022 - Current

- Homepage: sites.google.com/view/mdlt-p
- Jointly organized by OSI Lab, OptiML, and CSSPL
- · Topics: Learning theory, loss landscape, trajectory analysis, (stochastic) optimization, high-dimensional statistics, statistical/mathematical physics, scientific machine learning, and more.

KAIST 2021 Post-AI Research Project

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Undergraduate Researcher

May 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Jointly advised by Prof. Sangyoon Yi (SOIL Lab, GSFS, KAIST) & Prof. Jinkyoo Park (Sys. Int. Lab, ISysE, KAIST)
- Project: Research on 'Al-augmented Organizations' of Collaborative Decision Making and Learning
- Contribution: Devised a model-based randomized algorithm for single-player finite-horizon NK landscape optimization game

HANSEUL CHO (조한슬) UPDATE: JANUARY 1, 2023

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Individual Study

Mar. 2021 – Jun. 2021

- Advised by Prof. Jinwoo Shin (ALIN Lab, GSAI, KAIST)
- Study: (1) gradient-based optimizers for large-batch setting (e.g., LARS & LAMB); (2) theoretical analysis on gradient clipping

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Individual Study

- Advised by Prof. Jong-chul Ye (BISPL, BBE, KAIST)
- Assignment: Semantic Segmentation of Kidney Tumor with U-Net (with KiTS19 Challenge Dataset)

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Jun. 2020 - Aug. 2021

Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Individual Study

- Advised by Prof. Yeonseung Chung (MAS, KAIST)
- Study: Statistical Learning Theory

Awards_

2022	NAVER Outstanding Theory Paper Award, JKAIA 2022	Republic of Korea
2022	Summa Cum Laude, Bachelor's, KAIST	Republic of Korea
2017 - 2020	The National Scholarship for Science and Engineering, Korea Student Aid Foundation	Republic of Korea
2017 Fall	Dean's List , The School of Freshman, KAIST	Republic of Korea

Skills_

Programming Familiar: Python (PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Jupyter, Pandas, etc.), MATLAB. Novice: C, C++, R, HTML/CSS, Scalar **Miscellaneous** Familiar: £TEX (Overleaf/VSCode), Git, Microsoft Office. Novice: Adobe (Lightroom, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Photoshop).

Languages

English Sufficient for academic activities: TOEIC score 925 (LC 460, RC 465) (2021.04.11)

Korean Native proficiency

Others Had some introductory courses on French, German, Classical Latin, & Chinese.